<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Balachandar Blog</title>
    <link>https://balaca.github.io/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Balachandar Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://balaca.github.io/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommending Reddit communities with Google BigQuery</title>
      <link>https://balaca.github.io/2017/11/reddit-reco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://balaca.github.io/2017/11/reddit-reco/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:My previous post looked into most linked domains, in popular subreddits across the world. In that exploratary data analysis, I took a cluster of subreddits and did a comparative analysis of how (news-) domains linked, vary in their proportions within a cluster of subreddits. To a novice redditor though, it isn’t always clear which subreddits are alike, say, in terms of what they are about (for example, US Politics Wiki-rules), or, in terms of spatial proximity of subreddits, as extrapolated from redditors’ activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reddit top domains:  favorite news sources of redditors</title>
      <link>https://balaca.github.io/2017/10/reddit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://balaca.github.io/2017/10/reddit/</guid>
      <description>Reddit is a happening space to start conversations on any topical stuff with other anons in reddit community. Understandably though, it takes some initial effort on user’s part to figure how to get going in reddit aka the front page of the internet.
With thousands of user created communities out there to pick from (called subreddits in Reddit lingo), a new user will likely be at loss wondering how to pick the communities relevant to him or figure what sort of content gets discussed in communities that look interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TamilNadu 2016 Election - A Data Story</title>
      <link>https://balaca.github.io/2017/05/tamilnadu-2016-election---a-data-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://balaca.github.io/2017/05/tamilnadu-2016-election---a-data-story/</guid>
      <description>Ever since CN Annadurai of DMK uprooted INC, the sole dominant party then in 1967 elections, two dominant parties DMK and AIADMK had been alternating in throne for the most time in TamilNadu politics. One exception was December 1984 election when MG Ramachandran of AIADMK, incumbent Chief Minister then, won an absolute majority with 54% vote-share and retained his Chief Minister seat.
Fast forward 30 years, last May, we witnessed another such rarity when incumbent Chief Minister J Jayalalitha held onto her seat despite the anti-incumbency wave (partly from mishandling of floods), new parties mushrooming in the State and no popular party in AIADMK coaliation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>