<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Media on Balachandar Blog</title>
    <link>https://balaca.github.io/tags/social-media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Media on Balachandar Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://balaca.github.io/tags/social-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommending Reddit communities with Google BigQuery and the implicit library</title>
      <link>https://balaca.github.io/2017/11/reddit-reco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://balaca.github.io/2017/11/reddit-reco/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:My previous post looked into most linked domains in popular subreddits across the world. In that exploratary data analysis, I took a cluster of subreddits and did a comparative analysis of how (news-) domains linked, vary in their proportions within that cluster. It gave a glimpse of similar subreddits. To a novice redditor though, it isn’t always clear which subreddits are alike, say, in terms of what they are about (for example, US Politics Wiki-rules), or, in terms of proximity of subreddits, as extrapolated from redditors’ activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reddit top domains:  favorite news sources of redditors</title>
      <link>https://balaca.github.io/2017/10/reddit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://balaca.github.io/2017/10/reddit/</guid>
      <description>Reddit is a happening space to start conversations on any topical stuff with other anons in reddit community. Understandably though, it takes some initial effort on user’s part to figure how to get going in reddit aka the front page of the internet.
With thousands of user created communities out there to pick from (called subreddits in Reddit lingo), a new user will likely be at loss wondering how to pick the communities relevant to him or figure what sort of content gets discussed in communities that look interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>